

Thejoroop Reddy

Data science/Machine learning enthusiast

ADDRESS Bangalore

- Bangalore
- **** 8792680966
- thejoroop90@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/thejoroop-red dy-18469015a
- https://github.com/Thejoroop

SUMMARY

A Data science and Machine Learning enthusiast with 3+ years of strong working experience. Good statistical knowledge and ability to understand and find fine points of data. One year of hands on experience in python, data handling, data visualization, machine learning and SQL. Seeking a position which would enable me to combine technical and analytical skills to aid in meeting company goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python Machine Learning

Data Science Numpy
Pandas seaborn
scikit-learn SQL

MySQL Deep Learning

Predictive Modeling Data Visualization

Data Analysis

PROJECTS

Semiconductor manufacturing process

Objective: Build a classifier to predict the Pass/Fail yield of a particular process entity and analyse whether all the features are required to build the model or not

Algorithms used: Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random forest, AdaBoost, GradientBoost

Random forest performed well compared with other algorithms

Cross validation and GridSearchCV yielded better results

Model deployment using flask

Telecom Churn

The project is done by using ensemble models and it is a classification problem

Objective: Build a model that will identify the potential customers who have a higher probability to churn.

Algorithms used: Decision Tree, Random forest, AdaBoost, Gradient Tree Boosting

Gradient boosting performed well compared with other Algorithms with score of 82.45

https://github.com/Thejoroop/Telecom-churn.git

House price prediction

Objective: To predict the house price

Algorithms used: Linear regression, KNN, SVR, Decision Tree, Random forest, Gradient boosting

Best model: Gradient boosting(82% Training accuracy, 78% testing accuracy)

 $https://github.com/Thejoroop/Project 1/blob/main/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). Ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). Ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). Ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). Ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). Ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 gridsearch). Ipynbloomin/House_Price_Predictor (\% 20 after_interim \% 20 without \% 20 wit$

WORK EXPERIENCE

RRIT
Assistant Professor
(February 2017 - December 2018)

MaRS (January 2019 - August 2020)

Structural design engineer Sandary 2017 August 2020

EDUCATION

Acharya Institute of Technology (September 2009 - May 2013)

University visvesvaraya college of Engineering
ME Structural Engineering
(September 2013 - May 2016)

BE Civil Engineering

CERTIFICATIONS

Post Graduate Program in Machine Learning

Great Learning and Texas University

Python Programming Masterclass

Udemy